Okay, so in this video then, we are going
to talk about two more earned value
management terms, right, ETC, which is
estimate to complete, and VAC,
which is variance at completion.
Okay, so let's look at these two terms
then, right, estimate to complete.
Now, estimate to complete,
one that basically refers
to is essentially what's
left to spend on the project.
How much more money do we need to put
down, right, to finish up the project?
What's the first?
funding required essentially to finish up
the project between now and the end of the
project and that would be our estimate to
complete so let me ask you a very very
simple question right before we move on to
this just think of a very very simple
question let's say we're buying a car
we're purchasing a car and let's say we're
just paying cash and this car is going to
cost $20,000 right and um you put down
$2,000 as a deposit and I ask you what's
left for you to buy that car?
What's left to spend?
Well, what are you going to say?
$18,000, right?
That $18,000 is your ETC, your estimate to
complete.
Estimate to complete is what's left?
What's left to spend?
You put down $2,000 as a deposit,
the car's costing 20,000.
What's left, 18,000?
And that is exactly what ETC is,
right?
It's what is left to spend on your
project, right, between now and the rest
of the project, how much more money do we
need to put down in order to finish up?
So, what do we need to know?
We need to know how much money we've put
down so far, right, which is actual cost.
That's our actual cost, right?
And what our budget is,
what the project is actually
going to cost us now
at the end of the project.
Not what our original
budget is, but what our
project is actually
going to cost us, right?
Because they might end up going over
budget.
I mean, normally you end up going over
Right.
So what's our forecasted budget?
Our EAC.
So in our example that we've been using,
right?
So in the previous slide, we calculated
EAC.
Remember, there are four EAC formulas,
right?
But we really covered two
in more detail because those
are the two that are the more
common ones on the exam.
Right.
So let's just assume we are using that
second EAC formula assumption.
Right.
So another, other words, spending will
continue at the budgeted rate.
So we will not be going any further over
budget.
So right now, we are estimating our budget
to be $120,000.
We've spent $20,000 so far, or rather, we
have been over budget by $20,000 so far.
That's our cost variance.
We're $20,000 over
budget so far, and we're
just going to remain a
$20,000 over budget.
We're not going to go any further of a
budget, right?
So in that case then, our EAC,
as we figured out before, was 120,000.
So that's going to be our forecasted
budget.
We've spent $60,000 so far.
So what's left to spend?
Another 60,000.
Right.
So simply the formula for ETC is,
is EACC minus AC.
EAC.C minus AC.
If our EAC happened to be 130,000,
right, because of some of the assumption
that we make, right, then our ETC would be
70,000 in that case.
So ETC is what is left to
spend, right, what funding
we need between now
and the rest of the project.
VAC on the other hand, variance at
completion.
That is basically how much
over budget or under budget
we're expecting to be by
the end of the project, right?
How much over budget or under budget are
we expecting to be.
And that, again, all
of these formulas, all
of these terms are a
snapshot point in time.
So, how do we calculate that?
Well, we need to know our original budget.
We need to know our forecast the budget.
And so the difference is how
much over budget or under budget
we're going to be, you know,
by the end of the project.
So our original budget is 100,000.
Our forecasted budget, right, using the
assumption, you're using that assumption
that we're going to work
at the budgeted rate, or
work will continue at
the budgeted rate, right?
So with the EAC of 120,000, right?
So how much over budget or under budget
are we expecting to be?
$20,000.
And so the simple
formula is just BAC minus
EAC, original budget
minus forecasted budget.
If we use the third EAC formula,
right, remember spending will continue at
the current rate, right we will just
continue working at the same rate right
our forecasted budget was 150,000 in which
case then our VAC variance that completion
would be you know we're expecting to be
$50,000 over budget by then right but
we're using this assumption looks like
we're going to be $20,000 over budget
again negative negative is not good a
negative number it means that we're
basically over budget right we're going to
be over budget by $20,000 by the end of
the project That's not saying we're
$20,000 over budget right now.
It's saying based on our
expectations, it looks like
we're going to end up
being $20,000 over budget.
Right, by the end of the project.